That night at the hotel
结婚纪念日
we went to for our wedding anniversary…
住旅馆那晚…
when I was hugging Ichiko as she slept,
当我把小一搂在怀里时
I kept thinking about…
我一直在想…
Butcher.
屠屠
When winter came around,
冬天时
Butcher would crawl into my bed every night.
屠屠每晚都会爬到我床上
And I would fall asleep hugging that large body.
我就会搂着它胖胖的身体入睡
I definitely felt love and affection
她的温暖
in her warmth,
自然让我心生爱意
but that love and affection
但这种爱
are far removed from any feelings of desire or arousal.
却远非情欲或兴奋
Her warmth calmly soothed away my desire.
她的温暖平静地抚平了我的欲望
Sorry I made you wait, Otoya.
抱歉让你久等了 二也
-Excuse me, I'd like a beer. -Sure.
-劳驾来杯啤酒 -好
Looks like you're okay, Tohko.
姐 你气色不错
What? I guess so.
还行吧
Mom was worried about you.
妈妈之前还担心你
It was hard right after things ended.
刚分那会儿是挺难的
We'd been together since I was 20, after all.
毕竟我从20岁起就和他在一起了
That's half your life.
那是你的半辈子
Here's your beer.
您的啤酒
Thank you.
谢谢
Even so, we were pretty horrible to each other towards the end.
话虽如此 但到后来 我们闹得水火不容
I was so relieved when we divorced.
离了婚轻松多了
Then here's to making it through in one piece.
那这杯敬你成功度过难关
Thanks.
谢了
Bottoms up.
干杯
Delicious.
真好喝
Excuse me, can you take my order?
请问 我可以点餐吗？
Let's see. One marinated octopus, the boiled squid in ink,
我看看 一份调味章鱼、墨汁煮鱿鱼
and one simmered tripe, please.
还有炖牛肚 谢谢
And the two of you? No change?
你们俩呢？还是老样子？
Yeah, that's right.
嗯 是啊
-Is Ichiko doing well? -Yes. She told me to say hi for her.
-小一还好吗？ -嗯 她让我跟你问好
She said she'll go to the memorial.
她说会去参加追悼会
Okay.
好的
Oh, right.
哦 对了
Take a look at this.
你看这个
This was when I sent her that watermelon in the summer.
这是我那年夏天送她西瓜时拍的
Wow, look at Ichiko's carving.
你看小一刻的西瓜
She loved watermelons, so she was so happy.
她喜欢西瓜 所以很开心
But doesn't Ichiko look like a mess?
但这张小一是不是有点邋遢呀？
She probably thought this was the best photo of the watermelon.
她可能觉得这张西瓜拍得最好吧
Plus she spent all night on it.
她忙了一整晚呢
I really like this part of her.
我特别喜欢她这一点
Me too.
我也是
Look at you bragging.
瞧你得瑟的
The two of you really look like you're happily married.
你们俩看上去真恩爱呀
Thank you for waiting.
久等了
Thank you. It looks good.
谢谢 看上去很美味
It's a call from Ichiko's mom.
是小一的妈妈打来的
Why is she calling you?
她为什么给你打电话？
There are some things. I'm going to answer it.
有些事情 我接一下
Hello? Yes.
喂？是的
Thanks for the food.
我开动了
Okay, all right.
好的
Are you okay?
您没事吧？
All right.
好
Okay, I'll call Ichiko right away.
好的 我这就打给小一
BASED ON THE MANGA "1122" BY PEKO WATANABE
（根据渡边平子同名漫画改编）
1122: FOR A HAPPY MARRIAGE
电视剧名：1122 好夫妻
I feel it. This cold and dry air.
来了 这种又冷又干的空气
It's a nice place. It's quaint and nostalgic.
这里挺好的 有种别致的怀旧感
How long has it been since you've been back?
你多久没回来过了？
A year and a half, I think?
大概一年半吧？
I hope she didn't hurt herself too badly.
但愿她的伤不是太严重
It's so inconvenient to be in a cast.
打着石膏太不方便了
Thanks for coming with me, Otoyan.
谢谢你陪我来 二也
We've arrived.
到了
Time to go, huh?
我们走吧
How are you feeling, Mom?
妈妈 你感觉怎么样？
Here and there and everywhere,
还能怎么样
it's all bad.
处处不顺心
I keep bumping this cast into things,
这石膏总是磕磕碰碰
and it's so tight and painful.
勒得我生疼
The wind is too strong and my back hurts,
风太大 我又腰疼
so I can't even walk to the hospital.
所以连走去医院都做不到
What about a taxi?
那打车去呢？
That's such a waste of money.
那多浪费钱
I'm fine like this. It's okay.
我这样就行了 没关系
Mother,
妈妈
we made lunch. Would you like some?
我们做了午餐 您想吃点吗？
Wow, how pretty.
真漂亮啊
It's a rice sandwich.
是紫菜包饭
Ichiko made it because it's easy to eat with one hand.
小一做的 因为方便单手吃
Then I'll have one.
那我吃一块
Here.
来
You truly are kind, Otoya.
二也真是体贴啊
The complete opposite of him.
和那人完全不同
You're hardworking, not intimidating,
你手脚勤快 不会让人害怕
and so polite.
还特别温和有礼
You truly are.
真的
You even do housework.
你甚至会做家务
Ichiko, you really caught yourself a good husband.
一子 你真是钓了个好老公
Don't say I caught him.
别说什么钓不钓的
That man
那个人
truly thought of his wife as a servant.
就把我这个老婆当佣人
He would get drunk when stressed
一有压力就喝个烂醉
and get violent.
还会动粗
Even that hole.
那个洞
He made it when he threw the kettle.
是他扔水壶弄破的
I dodged it so I didn't get hurt,
我躲开了 所以没受伤
but I could have been badly burned.
但差点就被严重烫伤
Why don't you patch that hole? Actually, why not replace the whole thing?
你为什么不把洞补上？ 或者干脆换一扇拉门？
I can still use it. It would be a waste.
这门还能用 何必浪费钱
-I'll pay for it. -I said it's fine.
-我来出钱 -我说了不用
Don't you hate living with and seeing the marks of his abuse every single day?
这些暴力的痕迹 你整天看到不难受吗？
Here we go again.
又来了
The way you talk and look at me.
你说话的方式 还有看我的样子
It's just like him.
和那个人一模一样
How scary.
真可怕
I can't help it. I'm his child.
我没办法 我是他的骨肉
I know he's an abusive scumbag,
我知道他是个人渣
but half of my genes are his.
但我身上一半的基因是他的
But that isn't my fault.
这又不是我的错
You're lucky. You're not related to him by blood.
妈妈你运气好 和他没有血缘关系
And he's already dead.
而且他已经死了
Wasn't it your choice to live with it instead of trying to make things better?
忍气吞声 不跟他离婚 这难道不是你自己的选择？
Ichiko.
小一
I didn't catch the kind Otoya.
温柔体贴的二也不是我钓到的
I choose this life and work hard to maintain it.
我如今的生活是自己选的 而且我有用心维护
-You understand? -Ichiko.
-明白吗？ -小一
She's always been like this.
她一直都是这样
Treating me badly.
对我恶声恶气的
Strong-willed,
她自己有主见
always criticizing me,
总是挑我毛病
and blaming me. Just like her father.
什么事都怪我 和她爸一样
It must be hard for you, Otoya.
你真不容易 二也
Why don't I get you a cup of tea?
妈妈 我来帮您倒杯茶吧？
I bought some mooncakes.
我带了些月饼
Ichiko said you like them.
小一说您爱吃
Making tea for me. How nice of you.
真体贴啊 还帮我泡茶
Ichiko taught me how to do all the housework.
家务都是小一教我做的
Like how to fold laundry,
像叠衣服啦
and wrap dumplings.
包饺子啦
And how to make tea.
还有泡茶也是
Ichiko is a smart, honest, and cheerful woman.
小一聪明、诚实 而且乐观向上
So living together with her is fun.
所以和她一起生活很开心
I'm happy to be married to her.
能娶到她是我的福气
-Here. -Thanks.
-给 -谢谢
Otoyan.
二也
Thank you.
谢谢你
No need.
不用
You know…
那个…
I haven't talked about it much,
虽然以前很少提起
but can I tell you about my childhood?
但我可以跟你说说我的童年吗？
Sure.
好啊
When I…
那时候…
was a kid,
我还小
I had pediatric eczema.
得了小儿湿疹
When it was really bad,
发作得厉害时
my underwear, blankets, and stuff
我的内衣内裤 被子床单什么的
would be all covered in dead skin and body fluids.
上面全是死皮和体液
She would
她呢
make me wash everything
就会逼我 让我全部
by myself.
自己洗干净
And yell at me if I started scratching.
如果我痒了抓 她就会吼我
She barely ever held my hand.
她几乎从没牵过我的手
At night,
晚上
my dad, drunk, would sometimes hit her.
我爸爸喝醉酒 有时候会打她
I was so scared
我吓得要死
I couldn't even sleep. The next day…
睡不着觉 到了第二天…
Mom would tell me…
妈妈就会说…
I was cruel and heartless for not coming to her rescue.
我冷血无情 没良心 怪我没去帮她
All the time.
一直如此
I hate this house.
我讨厌这座房子
It pulls me back to the weak and hurt kid I used to be.
在这里 我会变回以前那个 无助、悲伤的小孩
My mom never treated me nicely…
我妈妈从来没有善待过我
so I can't bring myself to be kind to her just because she's weaker
所以现在我长大了 也没办法仅仅因为她上了年纪
now that I've grown up.
就孝顺善待她
You did your best, Ichiko.
你尽力了 小一
You're amazing.
你很了不起
I…
我…
can never be her caregiver.
永远没办法照顾她
Even now, I just want to smack her.
哪怕现在 我看到她就想扇她
You don't have to.
你不必勉强自己
I don't?
不必吗？
If it ever comes to that,
如果真到了那一步
let's think of a way that makes things easy for you.
我们可以一起想办法 让你少受点苦
Plus you've got me.
而且你还有我呢
Thank you.
谢谢你
I hate my mom.
我讨厌我妈妈
But I feel sorry for her.
但我也可怜她
You have a kind heart.
小一的心肠真好
I know you do.
我知道的
I…
我…
hate this house I was born in
讨厌我出生的房子
and the mother who gave birth to me…
也讨厌生下我的妈妈
but I'm really happy you are the family I chose to have.
但我真的很开心 选了你当我的家人
I think your child would be very happy.
将来你的孩子一定会很幸福
But we're…
但我们…
in a special situation right now.
眼下的情况有点特殊
Right?
对吧？
We are.
是的
All right.
好
Why don't we all go for lunch? My treat today.
大家一起去吃午饭吧？ 今天我请客
Really?
真的吗？
-Thank you. -Thanks for treating us.
-谢啦 -谢谢 你真客气
I'll have to pass.
我就不去了
-I brought lunch. -From your wife?
-我带了便当 -老婆做的？
No, I made it myself.
不 我自己做的
What? Why?
咦？为什么？
It's fun.
挺有意思的
I see.
这样啊
-You don't cook? -Nope, never.
-你不下厨吗？ -从来不
You're the type to take paternity leave, aren't you?
你属于那种会休陪产假的人吧？
Men also have the right to take leave, you know.
男人也有权休假啊
I didn't mean it that way.
我不是那个意思
MITSUKI KASHIWAGI SWEET DREAMS
（柏木美月 做个好梦）
GOOD NIGHT
（晚安）
YOU TOO, OTOYA
（你也是 二也 晚安）
AN ELEPHANT IN THE SKY
（天上的大象）
IT REALLY IS AN ELEPHANT!
（真的是大象呢！）
LUNCH BREAK?
（在午休？）
YEAH, I MADE MY OWN LUNCH TODAY
（嗯 今天我自己做了便当）
WOW AMAZING!
（哇！真了不起）
I WANT TO SEE WHAT YOU MADE!
（我想看你做的便当）
MORNING SUN NURSERY FOR SPECIAL EDUCATION
（朝阳特殊教育幼儿园）
THEN I'LL MAKE US A LUNCH BOX NEXT TIME
（那我下次也帮你做一份）
SO LET'S GO EAT IT SOMEWHERE
（那我们找个地方一起吃）
Mama!
妈妈
Hiro.
小宏
Go home.
回家
Let's change our shoes.
把鞋子换了
Can you sit here?
来坐下
Okay. Thank you for today.
好 今天多谢你了
He put on his jacket all by himself today.
今天他自己穿上了外套
He did?
真的呀？
Be sure to give him lots of compliments.
一定要好好表扬他啊
-Of course. -Go home.
-我会的 -回家
Mrs. Kashiwagi,
小宏妈妈
-his water bottle. -Oh, sorry.
-水杯 -抱歉
Thank you.
谢谢
Hiro.
小宏
-Goodbye. -Hiro, say, "bye-bye."
-再见 -小宏 说“再见”
-Sorry. -It's okay.
-不好意思 -没关系
Let's go.
我们走吧
Here I go.
我来咯
Hiro, should we play on the slide?
小宏 我们去玩滑滑梯好吗？
-Okay. -Hiro.
-接住了 -小宏
I'm throwing it.
我扔咯
-Stop!
-放手！
Stop it!
还给我！
Hiro, you can't. Give it back. Hiro.
小宏 不可以这样 还给她 小宏
Momo.
小桃
I'm so sorry.
真对不起
-Hiro, you need to say sorry. -He surprised you, huh?
-小宏 你得向她道歉 -他吓到你了吧？
Say you're sorry, Hiro.
说对不起 小宏
Hiro.
小宏
I wanna go home.
我要回家
Sure, let's go home.
好 我们回家
Come on.
走吧
-I'm really sorry. -It's okay.
-真的很抱歉 -没事
-Bye. -Bye-bye.
-再见
-Are you okay?
-你没事吧？
Should we go there to play?
我们去那边玩吧？
-Let's play over there. -Okay.
-我们去那边玩 -好
HIRO
（小宏）
MOTHER-IN-LAW
（婆婆）
It's really yummy.
这个很好吃哦
Say, "ah."
张开嘴
-Just one bite. -No!
-就吃一口 -不要！
Hiro. Here, "ah."
来 张嘴
Hey.
喂
Hiro.
小宏
-Play after you eat. -We are not home right now.
-吃完饭再玩 -我们现在不在家
Please leave your message after the beep.
请在“哔”声后留言
Hello, Mitsuki?
喂？美月？
It's Yoko. Did you get my text?
我是洋子 你收到我短信了吗？
The guru will be speaking in Tokyo next week.
那位老师下周在东京开讲座
I had them reserve seats in the front row,
我让人留了前排的座位
so please take Hiro with you.
你带上小宏一起去
She was kind enough to waive the entrance fee
老师特别客气 免了我们的入场费
for this lecture. She is so…
她真的是…
Hello?
喂？
Hi.
你好
Can you talk?
方便说话吗？
Yeah, I have time.
嗯 可以的
Sorry for calling you.
抱歉突然打给你
I wanted to hear your voice.
我就想听听你的声音
Mitsuki,
美月
how are you doing?
你还好吗？
I'm fine.
我很好
Hey,
对了
do you want to go out somewhere tomorrow?
明天你想出去走走吗？
With Hiro.
带上小宏
What do you think?
你觉得呢？
But Hiro might make a scene.
但小宏会调皮的
Let's go somewhere where it's okay if he does.
那我们就找个调皮也没关系的地方
The forecast says there is a 0% chance of rain tomorrow.
天气预报说明天的降雨概率为零
Otoya.
二也
-Good morning.
-早上好
Nice to meet you, Hiro.
小宏 初次见面
Hiro, this man is Otoya.
小宏 这是二也叔叔
Can you say, "Hi"?
打个招呼吧？
Wait, Hiro!
等等 小宏
Hiro.
小宏
Oh, here.
给你
Are you playing?
你在玩吗？
You're good at this, Mitsuki.
美月 你吹得真好
Here it comes, Hiro!
泡泡来啦 小宏
Wow.
好棒哦
Look, Hiro.
你看 小宏
It's your favorite. Hamburg steak.
是你最喜欢的汉堡排
Now,
那么
-thanks for the food. -Thanks for the food.
-我开动了
Which one do you want to eat?
你想吃哪个？
The Hamburg steak?
汉堡排吗？
Okay.
好
-Open wide. -Will he eat it?
-张大嘴巴 -他会吃吗？
-It's yummy. -Yummy?
-好吃 -好吃吗？
I made it a little too big.
做得太大了
Looks like it's okay.
应该没关系
You should eat too, Mitsuki.
你也吃吧 美月
I will.
那我开动了
Then I'll have the sandwich.
我吃块三明治
Me too.
我也吃一块
-It's good. -Thank goodness.
-好吃 -太好了
I think Hiro really enjoyed himself today.
今天小宏好像玩得很开心
That's good.
那就好
And you?
美月你呢？
Was it a good break for you?
你也有好好休息一下吗？
A very good break.
休息得非常好
He's already four,
这孩子四岁了
but they said he has a development delay of over a year in various areas.
但他们说他发育迟缓 很多方面落后同龄孩子一年
That's why I put him in specialized education early.
所以我早早让他上了特教班
My husband thinks childcare is entirely my responsibility,
我老公觉得带孩子完全是我的责任
and my mother-in-law
还有我婆婆
believes something made him this way.
她相信孩子这样是有原因的
She keeps nagging me
她笃信一个算命师
to take him to this fortune teller she's obsessed with
总催我带孩子去找那人算命
instead of the special classes.
不支持我们上特教
I know I have no choice
我知道我没别的选择
but to do all the research, consider all the options,
只能自己去研究、权衡
and make the decisions myself. However…
自己做决定 可是…
sometimes I just feel like giving up.
有时候干脆想放弃
Sorry. I didn't mean to complain.
抱歉 本来没打算跟你诉苦
The response was more positive than last time.
这次的反馈比上次好
Yes. I hope things continue like this.
是啊 但愿接下来也能一切顺利
It's our job to make sure it does.
所以我们要努力
Yes, sir.
对
Are you going back to the office?
你现在回公司吗？
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Mr. Kashiwagi?
柏木君？
See you again, Hiro. Bye-bye.
再见 小宏 拜拜
Hiro, say "Bye-bye."
小宏 说“拜拜”
Is it someone you know?
是你认识的人吗？
Yeah.
嗯
Welcome back.
你回来啦
I'm home.
我回来了
Shiro,
志朗
there's a dinner after the ikebana class next week. Is it okay if I go?
下周的花道课后 大家打算聚餐 我可以去吗？
I'll take Hiro to my mother's.
我会送小宏去我妈妈家
Sure.
好的
Thank you.
谢谢
Mitsuki.
美月
What did you do today?
你今天做什么了？
Today?
今天吗？
The weather was nice, so I took Hiro to the park.
天气很好 带小宏去公园玩了
So it was you. I thought I saw someone that looked like you when I was out.
原来真是你 我在外面看到一个人 就觉得像你
You did? You could have said hi.
是吗？那你应该打个招呼的呀
No, you were across the road.
不 我当时隔了条马路
Near the entrance?
在门口吗？
Yeah. Looked like you had a lot of fun.
对 你们看上去玩得很开心的样子
Who was that guy you were with?
和你在一起的那个男人是谁？
We ran into someone from the flower class.
碰到了花道班上的一个同学
I think he lives around there.
他好像住这附近
I see. The flower class.
花道班啊
Why don't you invite them over? Everyone from the class.
请班上的同学来家里坐坐吧？
I'd like to meet them.
我想认识一下
I can't do that.
那可不行
Why?
为什么？
The preparations and cleanup would be too much for me.
好多准备工作 还要收拾 我忙不过来
What if you get it catered?
那直接订餐呢？
I know someone who runs a catering company.
我有个熟人是开餐饮承办公司的
I hear the food both looks and tastes good.
我听说他们的食物看起来很棒 味道也很好
Thank you.
谢谢你
But I think everyone would feel awkward coming to my house and meeting you.
不过到家里来和你见面的话 大家应该会感觉不自在
It's more comfortable to split the bill at a diner.
还是在外面的小餐馆吃 然后分摊账单更好
Besides, you tend to judge my friends pretty harshly.
再说了 你总爱批评我的朋友们
Judge?
批评？
You say things like,
你会说
"that girl is a bit ugly, but she has a nice smile,"
“那女孩长得有点丑 但笑起来挺好看”
or "the way he eats and holds his chopsticks is a mess."
或者“那人的吃相真难看 筷子都不会拿”
Isn't the first one a compliment and the second one simply the truth?
第一个是夸奖 第二个只是实话实说 难道不是吗？
I never asked you to do that.
可那根本不是我要的
Anyway, I won't be inviting them over.
总之 我不会请他们来家里
All right.
这样啊
But, Shiro,
但是 志朗
I want to talk about your mother.
我想和你谈谈你妈妈
What about her?
她怎么了？
She said she wants that guru to have a reading with Hiro.
她说想让那个算命师帮小宏算命
I've told her no many times.
我已经拒绝很多次了
Now she says Hiro doesn't need to go for a reading,
现在她说 小宏不用去算命
but we should go to that guru's talk and give our greetings.
但我们得去参加那算命师的讲座 跟她打个招呼
I understand she's worried about him.
我知道她是担心小宏
And?
所以呢？
I want you to tell her.
我想让你去跟她说
We will not have anything to do with that guru.
我们不会找什么算命先生
Wasn't that what we decided on from the beginning?
这不是一开始就说好了的吗？
That's right.
是啊
But this is about Hiro, isn't it?
但这是关于小宏的事吧？
Aren't you in charge of raising him?
育儿的事不是美月你负责吗？
Did I say something wrong?
我说错什么了吗？
But aren't you his father?
但你不是他爸爸吗？
I am. That's why I work to make money.
是啊 所以我工作赚钱
That is my role.
那是我的职责
I'm very grateful to you.
我很感谢你的付出
You're doing something I can't.
你做了我做不到的事
That's why I left the special classes and support up to you.
所以我把上特教和辅导的事交给了你
I'll spare no expense
只要对小宏有帮助
if it's for Hiro.
多少钱都没问题
And you can just let my mother say whatever she wants.
我妈妈要说什么 你就随她说好了
She doesn't know any better.
她能懂什么
Make two or three templates and use them to respond to her.
准备两三个模板 用来回复她就行
Since you're a good mother.
你可是个好妈妈呢
Mama!
妈妈
Look, he's calling for you. Go to him.
他在叫你 快去吧
You go.
你去
It's impossible for me.
我不行
You already know that.
你是知道的
Mama!
妈妈
ATELIER IKKA
（一花工作室）
Everyone.
同学们
The calla lily has beautiful and dignified lines,
马蹄莲的线条优美端庄
so it can be used in place of branches like that.
所以可以用来代替枝条 就像那样
Let's arrange it so it can stand comfortable and free in its space.
我们来将它插好 让它自由舒展 亭亭玉立
-Yes.
-好
That looks great.
很漂亮
Sorry I made you wait.
抱歉让你久等了
Wow, this is gorgeous.
好丰盛啊
Like it came out of a magazine.
就像杂志上的图片一样
What an exaggeration.
太夸张了吧
You're so busy, it must have been hard to make this.
你那么忙 准备这些一定很辛苦
I was happy you made lunch for me that day.
那天你帮我做了便当 我很开心
Besides, I'm a housewife.
再说我是个家庭主妇嘛
Housewives have lots to do.
家庭主妇有好多事要做
Like chores for all three of you,
你们一家三口的家务
and taking care of Hiro.
还要照顾小宏
Thanks for the food.
我开动了
Delicious.
好吃
Otoya, you're a really nice person.
二也 你真是个好人
Otoya,
二也
we should probably be more careful when we go out in public.
我们去外面见面时 或许应该更小心一点
Did something happen?
出什么事了吗？
My husband said he saw us together
我老公说看到我们在一起
that day we went to the park.
就是去公园那天
Isn't that bad?
被发现了？
It was when we were saying bye outside the park,
是在公园外道别时
so I told him I ran into someone from the ikebana class.
所以我跟他说是遇见了花道班的同学
I just thought we were getting too careless lately.
我只是觉得 最近我们太不小心了
You're right.
是啊
Don't worry.
别担心
He doesn't know about us.
他不知道我们的事
He doesn't
他不知道
and I want to keep it that way.
我也不想让他知道
Nor do I want to end things with you. So I'm saying we should be more careful.
我也不想和你分手 所以我才说要小心点
I understand.
我明白
Wouldn't it be difficult for you too?
这对你来说也很难吧？
If your wife knew about us?
万一被你老婆知道
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Actually, Mitsuki,
美月 其实
my wife,
我老婆
she already knows what we're doing.
她知道我们的事
What?
什么？
She knows?
她知道？
Since when?
知道多久了？
Since the beginning.
从一开始就知道
What do you mean?
你什么意思？
We're
我和她
what you call sexless.
就是所谓的无性夫妻
It started with my wife saying no,
刚开始是因为她拒绝和我亲热
but when we talked about it,
但后来谈起时
she said she won't get involved in my love life or me having sex.
她说她不会干涉我的情感生活 也不介意我跟人上床
In other words,
也就是说
it's an authorized affair.
我找情人是她默许的
Is your wife okay with this?
你老婆不介意？
I think so.
应该吧
It hasn't been a problem so far.
到目前为止都没问题
I know
我知道
it's a very unique situation.
这种情况很特殊
But you have a good relationship with your wife, right?
但你和你老婆的关系很好吧？
Even without sex.
哪怕没有性生活
I think we do.
我们的关系是很好
Oh, but you're the only one I'm attracted to.
但我只对你有心动的感觉
I'm telling the truth.
是真的
So you're saying,
所以你是说
for me, you need attraction,
和我在一起 你需要心动的感觉
but you like your wife as a person?
而你喜欢你老婆 是喜欢她这个人？
That our relationship
我们的关系里
needs things like
必须有性爱
sex and lust.
有欲望
But there are feelings of love and trust
但你和你老婆之间
that go beyond head-over-heels love
是超越了激情的
between you and your wife?
爱和信任？
Of course there is.
果然如此
You're husband and wife. A family.
你们才是夫妻 是一家人
That's not how it is.
不是这样的
Am I
难道
some sort of cushioning
我的作用
that helps you keep the balance in your marriage?
就是用来缓和你们的夫妻关系？
So I'm bubble wrap?
我就是个气泡垫？
I said that's not it.
我说了不是这样的
Then what?
那是怎样？
I…
我…
I really cherished
我真的很珍惜
our relationship because I thought it was our secret.
我们的感情 因为我以为这是我们之间的秘密
But to be rolled around in the palm of your hand…
但被你玩弄于股掌间…
It's not even funny.
真的很没意思
Mitsuki.
美月
Don't take me for a fool.
别把我当傻子
Mama.
妈妈
I'm here.
我回来了
Look, Hiro. Mama's here.
小宏 你看 妈妈来了
Mama!
妈妈
Hiro.
小宏
Hello, dear.
宝贝
He cried the entire time?
他一直在哭吗？
Yeah, more than usual today.
是啊 今天哭得特别厉害
Go home. Go home.
回家
-I'm so sorry, Mom. -Don't worry about it.
-对不起 妈妈 -没关系
Shiro's always so busy.
志朗总是太忙
And you need a break too, sometimes.
而你有时也需要休息一下
-Thanks. -Oh, wait here.
-谢谢了 -等我一下
-Okay. -Go home.
-好 -回家
-Shall I carry you?
-要我抱你吗？
We're going home.
我们这就回家
Here, take these side dishes.
这些小菜你带回去
I made you plenty of simmered dishes and more.
我帮你做了不少炖菜什么的
But you have tenosynovitis.
可你有腱鞘炎呢
It's all right. This is the only time I can take care of you.
没事 只有这样我才能照顾到你
-Here, take it. -Thanks.
-来 拿着 -谢谢
Mama's here. Time to go home.
妈妈来了 该回家了
Can you put your shoes on?
你能把鞋子穿上吗？
You can do it.
你能行
-No. -Right, okay.
-不要 -好
I cooked for the man I'm having an affair with.
我为外遇的对象做饭
And bring home food from my mother who watched my son.
拿着妈妈做的饭回家 她还帮我照看孩子
I'm the worst.
我简直差劲透了
OTOYA - MITSUKI, I'M REALLY SORRY FOR TODAY.
（二也 美月 今天的事我很抱歉）
I WAS INSENSITIVE.
（我没有顾及你的感受）
I'M REFLECTING ON MYSELF.
（我已经在好好反省了）
YOUR FOOD WAS REALLY GOOD, I WAS HAPPY YOU MADE IT FOR ME.
（你做的东西很好吃 你为我做饭 我很开心）
I LOVE YOU
（我爱你）
GET HOME SAFELY.
（回家路上小心）
I LOVE YOU TOO
（我也爱你）
I can't stop.
停不下来
Even if I become the worst person ever.
哪怕变成世上最差劲的人
I just can't.
我就是停不下来
Why did the authorized affair
之前我们俩
we both agreed on
都同意的婚外情
start to feel wrong?
怎么感觉不太对劲了？
These are my own feelings. My own body.
这是我自己的感情 我自己的身体
But I have no idea why.
但我不知道为什么
SALON FLOWER GARDEN
（花园馆）
It's just a counseling session.
只是咨询一下而已
Cherry blossom tea is also served during occasions for celebration.
樱花茶也适用于庆祝场合
To say, "I hope the future blossoms for you."
寓意“祝君前程似锦”
Yes.
好
I mean, I see.
哦
Ms. Aihara, you requested the Body Extra course.
相原女士想要的是美体附加服务
Yes.
是的
I believe
我认为
sexual services are no different from going to the gym or aesthetician
性服务和健身、美容一样
to care for and please your body and mind.
都是为了呵护身心 愉悦自我
It is an important self-care routine.
是自我关爱的重要环节
That is why, instead of guilt, I want you to be curious and look forward to it
所以不要有罪恶感 要带着好奇心 心存期待
like you would when you go out to eat a delicious meal.
就像去餐厅享受美食一样
Of course we thoroughly take all precautions
当然 为了不辜负顾客的期望
to ensure our clients' trust and safety in order for you to feel that way.
我们采取了一切安全措施 确保顾客的信任和安全
Our salon's men are excellent at what they do.
我们的男孩子 手艺都很棒
I handpicked them myself.
全部由我亲自挑选
But it's best to meet them yourself.
但最好还是眼见为实
Oh, Rei.
礼君
Yes?
嗯？
What great timing. Can you come down?
来得正好 可以下来吗？
He's our most popular therapist.
他是这里人气最高的治疗师
Why don't you have a talk with him before deciding on a reservation?
不如在确定预约前 先和他聊聊？
Nice to meet you.
你好
Please, have a seat.
请坐
Thanks.
谢谢
I don't like younger guys.
我不喜欢比我小的男人
Not at all. Really.
一点也不喜欢
But…
但是…
Is it your first time using our services?
您是第一次来吗？
Yes.
是的
-I see. -This boy is absolutely shining.
-这样啊 -但这小子也太秀色可餐了吧
You don't need to be polite with me.
您不必跟我客气哦
Sure.
好的
My name is Rei. Like a ray of light.
我叫礼 礼貌的礼
I'm Ichiko Aihara.
相原一子
Ichiko.
一子
Nice to meet you.
请多指教
The power of a cute, younger man's smile is no joke.
年轻小帅哥的微笑 威力真是不容小觑
I used to make fun of those old men who get all excited by younger women.
我以前会嘲笑 见了小姑娘就春心荡漾的大叔
I am so sorry. I completely understand why now.
真是抱歉 现在我知道为什么了
Earlier,
刚才
when I saw you from up there,
在楼上看到你
and saw what a beautiful lady you are,
就觉得这位姐姐长得好漂亮
I got super excited.
于是心里特别开心
I know. I know.
我知道
I know it's only sales talk.
我知道这只是营销话术
No, that's not…
不 哪里…
I know, but
我明明知道
it's totally working. It's so good to hear.
却偏偏吃这一套 还听得心花怒放
If you choose me…
如果您指名我…
I will do my very best…
我定会尽心尽力…
to please you with all my heart.
做到让您满意
I made a reservation for the third Thursday of next month
我把预约定在了下个月第三个周四
with Rei.
指名了礼君
Great. Thank you.
好 谢谢你
I didn't even hesitate. Not one second.
我没有半刻犹豫 丝毫没有
-I got some on you. -No, it's fine.
-沾上唇膏了 -没关系
Otoyan.
二也
Should we buy a gift at the station
明天你外婆的追悼会
for your grandma's memorial service tomorrow?
我们在车站买份礼物吧？
I think that's good.
好主意
Hey, Ichiko.
小一
You should wash your fancy bras by hand. The lace will get damaged.
这种蕾丝胸罩应该手洗 放洗衣机会洗坏的
You know your stuff.
你可真是个行家
I was in charge of laundry at home.
我以前在家里就负责洗衣服
AIHARA FAMILY THIRD MEMORIAL SERVICE
（相原家 三回追悼会）
Here you go.
请用
Would you like a refill?
要给您满上吗？
-Here, Uncle. -Thanks.
-来 舅舅 -谢谢
You had it rough, Tohko. I heard you got a divorce?
灯子 听说你离婚了？真不容易啊
Hey, that's enough.
够了
That's right.
可不是嘛
Be honest, you're having a hard time, aren't you?
老实说 日子过得很辛苦吧？
I have my work, so I'm actually enjoying myself.
我在搞事业 其实还挺开心
Besides, the average life span is increasing.
再说了 人的平均寿命在延长
I might find someone else later.
说不定我以后能遇到别人
Find someone else?
遇到别人？
-You're already 40. -I'm 39.
-你都40岁了 -是39
Well, even if you get remarried, at that age, kids are out of the question.
就算能再婚 到时候以你的年纪 肯定要不了小孩
If you don't have kids soon, Otoya,
二也 如果你再不赶快要小孩
it will be the end of the Aihara family.
我们相原家就要绝后了
Children are society's treasure.
孩子是国家的花朵
The bond between husband and wife.
是夫妻之间的纽带
You know,
说起来
you'll have it hard if you don't have children to rely on when you get old.
要是老了以后膝下无子 你会很惨的
So, Ichiko, you should feed
所以一子要加油啊
Otoya plenty of food that helps him keep his vigor.
多给他吃些东西补补
-Uncle. -What?
-舅舅 -嗯？
We're doing just fine without a "bond."
我们之间没有那道“纽带” 照样过得很好
We won't do something as irresponsible as having kids so they can be our caregivers.
我们可不会光为了 老有所依就生孩子 太不负责了
-Irresponsible? You-- -Isn't it fine?
-不负责？你小子… -有什么关系？
I think it's good enough
他们俩夫妻恩爱
that they are happy in their marriage.
这就足够了
Besides, the family line will end when it ends.
再说 真要绝后也是没办法的事
The lives of the living are more important
比起过世的人和尚未出生的人
than those who are gone or have yet to be born.
活着的人好好生活才更重要
I learned that after I lost my husband.
我老公死后 我才明白了这个道理
Is that so?
是吗？
Here.
来
-Have another drink, Dad. -Thanks.
-再喝一杯 爸爸 -谢谢
Ichiko. Thank you for making time in your busy schedule to come.
小一 谢谢你 那么忙还抽时间赶过来
Thank you for inviting me.
谢谢您邀请我来
I'm happy to see you again after such a long time.
好久不见了 见到您我很开心
Sorry about my uncle.
我舅舅的话你别放在心上
It's perfectly fine.
我完全不介意
Mother had a good comeback.
妈妈答得多好呀
He's really a busybody.
他真够多事的
Otoyan's father passed away
二也的父亲
early in life.
走得早
Despite that,
尽管如此
or is it because of that,
还是说 正因如此
there is a strong bond of trust between the three of them.
他们一家三口之间感情深厚
Moreover, they are quite free-spirited.
而且都是随心所欲的乐天派
Let's go drinking again, Ichiko.
我们再去喝点东西吧 小一
Without the annoying nagger this time.
这次不带那个长舌大叔
In that case, absolutely.
那敢情好
I think that was my salvation.
我想 这就是我的救赎吧
Take care.
保重
Bye.
再见
Wait, Otoya.
等一下 二也
This.
这个
-These are extra. Take them. -We already have one.
-是剩下的 你拿去 -我们已经有了
Just take it.
你拿着就是了
But there are moments
但有时候
when I get jealous of the things my husband has
我会妒忌我老公 他拥有一些宝贵的东西
that I don't.
而我没有
A close family.
相亲相爱的一家人
A close relationship with his mom.
母子之间亲密无间
Okay. But Mom should take one too.
好吧 但这个妈妈拿去
Home sweet home.
到家啦
It's good to be home.
终于到家啦
Good to be home.
回家真好
I'm really sorry about my uncle.
我舅舅那样 真对不起啊
He's really conservative.
他就是个老古董
It's okay.
没事
And it's true I'm 35,
确实 我35岁了
so there will always be people giving me advice like that.
到处有人这么劝我
Maybe I should have been more direct.
或许我该直接一点
And tell him he was being rude.
说他没礼貌
You said enough.
已经很好了
Your mother and sister even came to my defense.
你妈妈还有你姐都帮我说话了
Thanks.
谢谢
Hey, Otoya.
二也啊
Do you ever think about having kids?
你有考虑过要小孩吗？
I don't know.
不知道
I haven't given it much thought.
还没怎么考虑过
Right?
是吧？
It's still a vague idea for me too.
我也还没怎么考虑呢
Well, I shouldn't be saying "still" at my age.
好吧 我这年纪不该说“还”
Yeah.
好吧
Anyway, me too.
嗯…我也是
I could have my own "thing" too.
哪怕是我 现在起也可能会发生些什么
Why have I never thought
我怎么从没想到
that Ichiko could also have an affair?
小一也可能会有婚外情呢？
I keep thinking about that lacy bra I saw for the first time.
突然出现的蕾丝胸罩 在我脑中挥之不去
It's not like I'm disparaging her.
我不是在贬低她
Nor am I being conceited.
也没有自以为是
I just never thought about it.
我只是从没想过这些
I took our trust for granted.
把夫妻间的信任当作理所当然
Is it because I'm an idiot in love?
难道是因为 在爱情上我就是个笨蛋？
Probably yes.
或许吧
If Ichiko exercises her right to have an authorized affair,
如果小一按婚外恋许可制 行使她的权利 有了外遇
she would fall in love with another man,
她就会爱上别的男人
and if she has sex with him…
如果她和对方上床…
No, if she already slept with him…
不 如果她已经跟他上床了…
Today is the third Thursday of the month.
今天是这个月的第三个周四
The one night out of the month my husband sleeps with his lover.
是我老公每月一次 和情人过夜的日子
And today
今天
marks the very first time I'm visiting a brothel.
我第一次去风俗馆
THIS IS A WORK OF FICTION.
（本故事纯属虚构）
Subtitle: Annie Chen
字幕翻译：纪小敏